(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, and
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today with Erica, we have
an upper-intermediate lesson.
- That's right.
An upper-intermediate
lesson that's a little bit strange,
it's a little bit strange,
but it's a real English lesson
because that's what we
give you here at English Pod.
- So in today's lesson, we've got a
lot of really great language for you.
We've got language to
help you to gossip better.
- Gossip, why don't you
explain it a little bit, just in case.
- Okay, so if I gossip, I maybe
share news or information
about other people with my friends,
like I might say something like, " Marco,
did you see what happened
in Chinese pod today?
You'll never guess what I saw.
" - Exactly, that's gossip.
And we also have
language today to describe
things, to describe strange
things, strange things.
All right, so let's take a look
at our vocabulary preview.
- Very vocabulary preview.
- So in our vocabulary preview,
we'll look at a few important words
that will help you to understand
the dialogue a little bit better.
- Exactly, and the first
word is weird, weird, weird.
Now this is a common word you probably hear
all the time and in a lot of different
situations, so we wanted to explain it today.
- Yeah, this word just means strange.
- It's strange, weird
person is a strange person.
- Exactly, but the
thing about this word is,
if you are a young person,
let's say under the age of 35,
you'll probably use it
about 100 times a day.
(laughing)
- Weird.
- Yeah, it's just such a
good sounding word, weird.
- It is.
- Okay, but the thing
is that, even though it's
probably more commonly
used in American English,
it's still widely used for
British English as well.
- Yeah, that's true.
- So, but maybe in British English,
you would say something like, "odd.
" - It's odd, that's
more common.
- Okay, let's look at our second word.
- Housewarming gift.
- Now this is a cultural thing.
It's really common in North America
to give a housewarming gift to someone.
- Yeah, if I move into a new house,
maybe some of my friends or family
will bring a gift over to make
my house a little bit more beautiful.
- So something like a photo frame or--
- Or maybe a plant or sometimes even
like maybe a basket of
pastries or something.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- I've never gotten one of those.
- Really?
- I didn't have a home.
- Where do you live on the street?
- Well, I don't have my own home,
so I had never gotten one of those.
- Okay.
- Okay, so we're ready
now to listen to our dialogue.
- So we've got two
housewives who are gossiping
about what's going on in the neighborhood
and let's listen to what happened.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, I don't know if you've heard
that someone moved into
that old house down the road.
- Yeah, I know.
I met the owner of the house
yesterday as he was moving in.
His name is Armand.
- Really?
- I was like, you have to fill me in.
- Actually, he's a bit strange.
I don't know.
I've just got a bad feeling about him.
- Really?
- Why?
- Well, yesterday I brought
over a housewarming gift,
but Armand started acting really weird
and then he practically kicked me out.
I tried to sort of peek into
his house, but everything
was so dark inside that I
couldn't really get a good look.
The whole thing really creeps me out.
- Well, you'll never guess
what I saw this morning.
It's a livery truck pulled into his driveway
and it dropped off a long rectangle box.
It almost looked like a coffin.
- You see?
- The wiper key.
- Oh, ladies.
- Armand!
You scared the heck out of me.
This is my friend Doris.
- I'm a pleasure to meet you.
If you're not doing anything tonight,
I'd like to have you both for dinner.
I mean,
I'd like to have you both over for dinner.
- That guy seems kind of weird.
You can hear his voice
is like a weird guy, right?
- Yeah.
All right, let's take a
look at our language
takeaway and look at
some of these great words.
- Language takeaway.
So our language takeaway
focuses on several words
from the dialogue that we feel
are really important for you to know.
- Exactly.
And we have four of them for you today.
Why don't we look at the first one?
- Okay, so the first word is a bad feeling.
- Bad feeling.
- A bad feeling.
- So we've got a few examples that will help
you to understand how this phrase works.
Example one.
I don't like Kelly's new boyfriend.
I've got a bad feeling about him.
Example two.
- It's so dark.
We shouldn't be out here.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
- Example three.
I've got a bad feeling about this trip.
I feel like something's going to happen.
Maybe we shouldn't go.
Okay, so basically you think
something bad is gonna happen.
Yeah, you have a sort
of uncomfortable feeling.
Okay, that makes sense.
I have a bad feeling about something.
Exactly.
Okay, let's look at our second word now.
Kicked me out.
So when someone kicks you
out, it's, they force you to leave.
You don't want to leave,
but they force you to.
Yeah, Marco, have you ever
kicked someone out of your class?
Yes, I have.
Really?
Yeah, if you misbehaved in
my class, you're kicked out.
So you're pretty strict.
Sometimes I am.
Okay, also maybe you've
kicked your husband out of bed.
I might have done that
once or twice or more.
We'll have to ask him, I'm sure he has.
All right, so that's what it means.
Before someone to leave the
house, leave the class, leave the bed.
So kicked out of class, kicked
out of the house, kicked out of bed.
Exactly.
Great.
Let's look at our third word now.
Kicked me out.
Kreeped me out.
Now this is a really common phrase.
I like this phrase a lot
and we've got some
examples for you to listen to to help you
understand this word a little bit better.
Number one, did you know that?
Oh, I think I saw something.
Stop it.
You're really creepy me out.
Example two.
This place really creeps me out.
Let's get out of here.
All right.
Confession to make, I'm
kind of creeped out by clowns.
You are.
I don't know.
They're just creepy.
They scare me.
Really?
Yes.
What is it about clowns
that scare you so much?
I don't know.
They're just white faces and weird paint.
It's just creepy.
The way they laugh.
I don't know.
Maybe at a bad experience
with clowns as a child?
Probably.
I watched the scary movie
about clowns or something.
Yeah.
All right.
So creeped me out.
Made me feel uncomfortable.
Yeah.
Well, speaking of being scared, we have
our final word for a language takeaway.
And it is scared the heck out of me.
You scared the heck out of me.
Scared the heck out of me.
You got really scared.
Yeah, I think this is a quite common way
of saying, you really, really scared me.
Yeah.
OK, we're ready to listen
to our dialogue again.
Now try and see if you can catch all
these phrases that we just talked about.
Oh, I don't know if you've heard,
but someone moved into
that old house down the road.
Yeah, I know.
I met the owner of the house
yesterday as he was moving in.
His name is Armand.
Really?
What's he like?
You have to fill me in.
Actually, he's a bit strange.
I don't know.
I've just got a bad feeling about him.
Really?
Why?
Well, yesterday I brought
over a housewarming
gift, but Armand started
acting really weird.
And then he practically kicked me out.
I tried to sort of peek into
his house, but everything
was so dark inside that I
couldn't really get a good look.
The whole thing really creeped me out.
Well, you'll never guess
what I saw this morning.
A delivery truck pulled into his driveway
and it dropped off a long, rectangular box.
It almost looked like a coffin.
You see?
Why would he-- Hello, ladies.
Ah, Armand!
You scared the heck out of me.
This is my friend, Doris.
A pleasure to meet you.
If you are not doing anything tonight, I
would like to have you both for dinner.
I mean, I would like to have
you both over for dinner.
You know, one of the things I really
like about this dialogue
is there's a lot of
great phrases that
will help you to gossip.
That's a good observation.
So I think it's time for Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
In Fluency Builder, we take a
simple phrase or a simple word
you already know and
show you how to express
the same idea a little
bit more naturally.
OK, great.
So let's take a look at our
first item for Fluency Builder.
So when you gossip with
somebody, you often tell them
news or information that
they don't know already.
And you might start by
saying, did you know that?
Or you can say, did you hear?
Yeah, both of those
phrases are perfectly fine.
But if you want to sound a little bit
more native-like when you're gossiping,
you might try out this
phrase from the dialogue.
I don't know if you've had.
Yeah, that's a really good phrase.
You're saying exactly the same
thing, but in a really natural way.
It's a great one for gossiping.
So Marco, I don't know if you've heard,
but Chinese pod is up to
some pretty crazy things.
See, that's exactly how
you would use that phrase.
So now let's take a
look at our second item.
Now, when you're gossiping,
you want information.
That's right, so you might
say, oh, tell me about it.
Or something like, give me the details.
Yeah, and again, both of these examples
are perfectly fine, but
when you're gossiping,
you might want to
try something like this.
You have to fill me in.
Fill me in, yeah, that's what I would say.
Fill me in, you know, give me the details.
Fill me in.
Fill me in on today's gossip.
OK, so let's take a look at our third item.
Now, if you have some juicy
gossipy news, and you want to
start up a conversation, you
might use this phrase here.
Well, you'll never guess
what I saw this morning.
That's a really good phrase.
You can change it a little bit.
You can say, you'll never guess who I saw.
Or you'll never guess what I heard.
Exactly.
Very excellent gossip phrases.
We're teaching you how to
gossip, because that's real English.
People really do it, so you
got to know the language for it.
All right, so enough of our gossip.
I think it's time for us to listen
to the dialogue one last time.
Oh, I don't know if you've heard
that someone moved into
that old house down the road.
Yeah, I know.
I met the owner of the house
yesterday as he was moving in.
His name is Armand.
Really?
It's like you have to fill me in.
Actually, well, he's a bit strange.
I don't know.
I've just got a bad feeling about him.
Really?
Why?
Well, yesterday I brought
over a housewarming gift,
but Armand started acting really weird,
and then he practically kicked me out.
I tried to sort of peek into
his house, but everything
was so dark inside that I
couldn't really get a good look.
The whole thing really creeps me out.
Well, you'll never guess
what I saw this morning.
A delivery truck pulled into his driveway,
and it dropped off a long rectangle of box.
It almost looked like a coffin.
You see?
To wipe the key.
Oh, ladies.
Armand, oh, you scared the heck out of me.
This is my friend Doris.
I'm a pleasure to meet you.
If you're not doing anything tonight,
I'd like to have you both for dinner.
I mean, I'd like to have
you both over for dinner.
Okay, Marko, I have a true story for you.
Is it kind of like a creepy story?
It is a creepy story indeed.
Is it a true story?
No, it's really true.
So when I was young, I
used to live in the country,
and in the country, all of the
neighbors know each other.
It's a small community, so everyone
knows what's happening all the time.
Okay.
And there was some gossip
going on in our community
about a guy who lived
at the end of the road,
and he was the owner
of a car wrecking yard.
So a place where you take old broken
down cars and take the parts apart to sell.
Right.
Anyway, a scrap yard.
Yeah, a scrap yard.
All right.
So, you know, he had a wife and a couple
of kids, and suddenly his wife disappeared.
Wow.
Yeah.
And no one knew what happened or anything.
And so several years passed,
and suddenly the police
start coming in and
start investigating this guy
and start digging up all of
the land around his property.
And I guess I don't
know what they're doing,
but I think they were
looking for the wife's body.
Wow, and did they find it?
I don't know, I moved away.
(laughs)
Such a great story, but
we don't know how it ends.
Yeah.
Well, we can leave it up to
the imagination of our listeners.
Exactly.
Maybe they were looking for an old car.
An old car buried in the ground.
I don't think so.
All right, that's a true story,
real English, real stories.
You heard it first here on English Pot.
All right.
So we wanna hear your comments
and suggestions about this topic.
I bet a lot of our listeners also have
creepy stories, maybe ghost stories, maybe,
I don't know, different
types of weird stories.
So you guys should definitely log on
to English Pot and share them with us.
That's right, go to englishpot.
com and in the comments section of
the website, tell us your creepy stories.
And we're gonna pick out the
best story as the story of the week.
We'll announce it in
our This Just In podcast.
Yes, so we wanna hear all your juicy
stories and gossip, maybe, as well.
Yes, all right.
Well, it's time for us to go.
So be sure to listen to us next time.
But until then, it's bye-bye.
Bye.
(upbeat music)